Indiana University Retirees Association records, 1975-2019 C291
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Retirees Association records
1975-2023
1977-1998
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Retirees Association
C291
1 cubic foot 1 rc box
Established in 1975 as the Annuitants' Association of Indiana University, the Indiana University Retirees Association is an organization for retired IU employees. Its primary purpose is to make information on retirement funds and on local social activities available to its members. The IU Retirees Association records contains correspondence with university administrators, minutes of the board, membership rosters, and copies of the association's newsletter, Newswatch.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Administrative History
The Annuitants' Association was established in 1975 to inform retired faculty and staff members enrolled in the TIAA-CREF retirement program about social and educational activities in the Bloomington area, as well as to provide information on retirement funds to its members. The brainchild of Chancellor Herman B Wells and Professor Harry Sauvain, the Association grew steadily in the decades after its founding and continues to have strong support today. In 2004, the name changed to the IU Association of Retired Faculty and Staff and in 2010, the name changed again to the IU Retirees Association. According to a history posted on the group's web site (http://www.indiana.edu/~iura/detailed-history.html), retirees from all IU campuses, their spouses or partners, widows or widowers, are welcomed into membership.
Arrangement
The IU Retirees Association collection is organized into three series: Administrative files, Membership records, and Publications.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the IU Retirees Association span the period from 1975-2019, and are organized into 3 series: Administrative files, Membership records, and Publications.
The Administrative files series consists of the general records of the organization, including ballots, financial records, meeting minutes and accompanying documents, and correspondence. The correspondence found within the collection includes letters to members of the association, lawyers, attorneys, and the heads of annuitants' associations at other universities, as well as other miscellaneous correspondence.
The Membership series includes lists of association members from the early 1980s through 2008 as well as board membership rosters from 1975-2007. The lists generally include addresses only, but occasionally phone numbers are listed.
The Publications series includes a brief history written around 2007 by long time member J. Robert Dodd as well as the monthly Newswatch newsletters created by the Association. The run of newsletters is not complete.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Archived web sites for this organization may be included in Archive-It
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Accrual Information
The University Archives regularly receives current issues of the Newswatch newsletter; these issues are added to the Publications series at the end of each calendar year.
Acquisition Information
Accession numbers: 2003/045, 2003/130, 2006/005
Provenance
Transfer from the Association.
Retirees --Education --Indiana --Bloomington --History --Sources.; Indiana University Retirees Association -- Archives; Indiana University Retirees Association -- Records and correspondence
- Administrative files, 1975-2021 (Box 1)
  - Articles of Association, 1979-2005 (Box 1)
  - Articles and bylaws, 2014 (Box 1)
  - Ballots, 1975-1980 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes (Box 1)
    - 1975-1994 (Box 1)
    - 1995-2015 (Box 1)
    - 2013 (Box 1)
    - 2018-2019 (Box 1)
    - 2019-2020 (Box 1)
    - 2020-2021 (Box 1)
  - Conference, 1992-2012 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1975-2010 (Box 1)
  - Financial Records, 1977-1978; 2012-2016 (Box 1)
  - Health Care, 1991-2012 (Box 1)
  - Operations Manual, 2010 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 2018-2021 (Box 1)
    - 2018-2019 (Box 1)
    - 2019-2020 (Box 1)
    - 2020-2021 (Box 1)
- Membership records, 1975-2021 (Box 1)
  - Board Membership directories, 1975-2009 (Box 1)
  - Membership directories (Box 1)
    - 1980s (Box 1)
    - 1990s, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - 2004-2008 (Box 1)
    - 2009-2010 (Box 1)
    - 2018-2019 (Box 1)
    - 2019-2020 (Box 1)
    - 2020-2021 (Box 1)
  - Membership report, 2014 (Box 1)
  - Widows lists, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
- Publications, 1980-2023 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Note: Newsletter run is incomplete
  - "A Brief History of the Indiana University Annuitants' Association," by J. Robert Dodd, circa, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Brochure, circa, 2010? (Box 1)
  - Meeting notices and news bulletins, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Newswatch (Box 1)
    - 1989-1993 (Box 1)
    - 1994-1998 (Box 1)
    - 1999-2005 (Box 1)
    - 2006-2008 (Box 1)
    - 2008-2009 (Box 1)
    - 2009-2010 (Box 1)
    - 2011-2012 (Box 1)
    - 2011 (Box 1)
    - 2013-2014 (Box 1)
    - 2015 (Box 1)
    - 2016 (Box 1)
    - 2017 (Box 1)
    - 2018 (Box 1)
    - 2019 (Box 1)
    - 2019-2021 (Box 1)
    - 2022 (Box 1)
    - 2023 (Box 1)